[Music]
Too many communities have been touched by armed violence.
Sandy Hook, Columbine, Virginia Tech, New Life Church
Each time such an event happens in another community, it touches us as a nation.
And we are reminded that it could happen in our own community.
Mass casualty incidents may occur wherever people congregate.
In elementary and secondary schools
On college campuses
In houses of worship
Or in other venues
They are part of a complex problem that affects the entire community.
and that will require the whole community working together to address
While no measures can ensure absolute security
There are ways that we can significantly reduce the risk.
Many planned attacks have been averted and countless lives have been saved
By being prepared
By sharing our collective insights, expertise, and effort
We can minimize the likelyhood that such events will take place
And be prepared to act if an incident does occur
Are you prepared?
This course will help you understand the threats and challenges of mass casualty incidents.
and present ways you can improve your level of preparedness should the unthinkable occur.
[music]